Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another sci-fi lesson for all of those fans out there of
今天我们要为所有《星际迷航》和《星球大战》的粉丝带来另一节科幻课。
Star Trek and Star Wars.
《星际迷航》和《星球大战》。
That's right.
没错。
And today we're going to focus on some phrases.
今天我们将重点学习一些短语。
We're not going to do any vocabulary today.
今天我们不讲词汇。
We're just going to learn some phrases that you'll find relating to science fiction.
我们只学习一些与科幻相关的短语。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So why don't we listen to a dialogue for the first time and we'll come back and look at
那我们第一次听对话吧，听完后再回来看这些短语。
all these phrases.
所有这些短语。
Captain, we are under attack by an unidentified ship.
舰长，我们正遭到一艘不明飞船的攻击。
Damage report.
损伤报告。
We've sustained heavy damages to the engines.
引擎遭受了严重损坏。
We've lost our warp drive.
我们失去了曲速引擎。
We'll have to attempt to make contact.
我们必须尝试建立联系。
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard of the Starship Enterprise.
我是企业号星舰的让-吕克·皮卡德舰长。
We don't wish to engage.
我们不想交战。
What is the nature of this attack?
这次攻击的性质是什么？
I am Captain Kor of the ship Kortos, your ship attack that will search party.
我是科托斯号飞船的科尔舰长，你的飞船攻击了我们的搜索队。
No, you're not doing it right.
不，你演得不对。
Kor doesn't sound like that.
科尔的声音不是那样的。
His voice is deeper.
他的声音更低沉。
I am Captain Kor of the ship Kortos, your ship.
我是科托斯号飞船的科尔舰长，你的飞船。
No, if you can't do an authentic Klingon voice, I'll have to find a more serious Star Trek
不，如果你不能发出地道的克林贡语声音，我得找一个更认真的《星际迷航》粉丝，一个真正会演戏的，行吗？
fan who can actually act, okay?
一个真正会演戏的，行吗？
But, but, I already bought the Klingon suit and the wig and...
但是，但是，我已经买了克林贡套装和假发……
All right, very good Star Trek fans.
好了，非常棒的《星际迷航》粉丝们。
Apparently, they were trying to act out one of the famous episodes where the Klingons
显然，他们是在尝试表演克林贡人攻击企业号的著名剧集之一。
attack the Enterprise.
攻击企业号。
My goodness.
天哪。
I don't know a lot about Star Trek, but I do know a lot about language and we've got
我对《星际迷航》了解不多，但我对语言了解很多，我们这里有一些很棒的内容，能帮助你更好地理解英语科幻电影和电视剧。
some great stuff here that will help you understand sci-fi movies and TV shows in English a little
一些很棒的内容，能帮助你更好地理解英语科幻电影和电视剧。
bit better.
更好地理解。
So, why don't we go now to Fluency Builder?
那我们进入“流利度构建”环节吧。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right, so the first phrase that we have today on Fluency Builder, unidentified ship.
好的，今天在“流利度构建”中的第一个短语是“unidentified ship”（不明飞船）。
An unidentified ship.
不明飞船。
Unidentified ship.
If we break it down and look at the first word, unidentified.
如果我们分解来看，第一个词是“unidentified”（不明的）。
You don't know which one it is.
你不知道它是哪一个。
Okay, you don't know the identity.
对，你不知道它的身份。
Yep.
是的。
And a ship, I guess that's short for...
而“ship”（飞船），我猜是……的简称。
A rocket ship.
火箭飞船。
Or a spaceship.
或者宇宙飞船。
Okay.
好的。
So, we're not talking boats here.
所以我们这里说的不是船。
All right.
好的。
We're not talking about boats.
我们说的不是船。
Very good.
非常好。
So, the next phrase, the Enterprise lost its warp drive.
下一个短语，企业号失去了它的曲速引擎。
Warp drive.
曲速引擎。
So, the warp drive of the Enterprise is actually something like an engine that allows it to
企业号的曲速引擎实际上是一种能让它超光速飞行的引擎。
go faster than the speed of light.
超光速飞行。
So, super fast.
所以是超快。
Super fast.
超快。
But why warp?
但为什么叫“warp”（曲速）？
All right.
好的。
Well, if we take a look at the word warp, that actually means to bend.
嗯，如果我们看“warp”这个词，它实际上意思是弯曲。
Yep.
是的。
So, like when you warp wood, it bends.
就像你弯曲木头时，它会变形。
Exactly.
没错。
You bend wood or you warp metal.
你弯曲木头或弯曲金属。
And well, that's kind of the theory behind it is that they're going so fast that they
嗯，这背后的理论是，它们飞得太快，以至于弯曲或扭曲了时间。
bend or warp time.
弯曲或扭曲了时间。
Okay.
好的。
So, warp drive.
所以是曲速引擎。
I think a very sci-fi specific phrase here.
我认为这是一个非常科幻的特定短语。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
And for our third phrase today, search party.
今天我们的第三个短语是“search party”（搜索队）。
Search party.
搜索队。
A search party.
Okay.
好的。
So, what is this?
这是什么意思？
Are we having a party?
我们要开派对吗？
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Well, when somebody gets lost, you know, maybe in the woods or something, you send out a
嗯，当有人迷路时，比如在森林里，你会派一个搜索队去找他们。
search party to find them.
搜索队去找他们。
So, a party would be a group of people.
所以“party”可以指一群人。
Exactly.
没错。
So, that also happens in restaurants, I think, right?
这在餐厅里也会发生，对吧？
Right.
对。
Sometimes you might say how many people in your party.
有时你可能会问“你们一行有几位？”。
In your party.
你们一行。
Very good.
非常好。
So, party, group of people.
所以“party”就是一群人。
All right.
好的。
So, in the dialogue, we saw that actually these were not real Star Trek characters,
在对话中，我们看到这些其实不是真正的《星际迷航》角色，他们只是在表演。
but they were just acting.
他们只是在表演。
But it didn't sound quite right, right?
但听起来不太对劲，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
He said that his voice is deeper.
他说他的声音更低沉。
So, a deep voice.
所以是低沉的声音。
Deep voice.
低沉的声音。
A deep voice.
All right.
好的。
We're going to hear an example of what a deep voice sounds like.
我们来听一个低沉声音的例子。
The one constant through all the years, Ray, has been baseball.
多年来唯一不变的东西，雷，就是棒球。
America has rolled by like an army of steamrollers.
美国像一支蒸汽压路机大军一样滚滚而过。
It's been erased like a blackboard, rebuilt and erased again.
它像黑板一样被擦掉，重建，再被擦掉。
That is a deep voice.
这就是低沉的声音。
Now, because his voice wasn't deep enough, he didn't sound authentic.
因为他的声音不够低沉，所以他听起来不地道。
Authentic.
地道的。
All right.
好的。
So, authentic, very easy word.
“Authentic”（地道的）这个词很简单。
Real.
真实的。
True to life.
逼真的。
Real.
真实的。
True to life, right?
逼真的，对吧？
Not fake.
不是假的。
Exactly.
没错。
So, Marco, is that an authentic Rolex?
那么，Marco，那是地道的劳力士吗？
No, it's not.
不，不是。
But thank you for noticing.
但谢谢你的注意。
All right.
好的。
So, authentic.
所以是“authentic”（地道的）。
And our last word for today.
今天最后一个词。
A wig.
假发。
W-I-G.
W-I-G。
Wig.
假发。
So, a wig is pretend hair, right?
假发就是假头发，对吧？
Right.
对。
Fake hair.
假头发。
So, the hair is not authentic.
所以这头发不是真的。
Very good.
非常好。
All right.
好的。
So, a wig.
所以是假发。
All right.
好的。
We've got some great language here.
我们学到了一些很棒的语言点。
Why don't we listen to it one more time, slowed down a little bit, in the dialogue.
我们再用慢速听一遍对话吧。
Captain, we're under attack by an unidentified ship.
舰长，我们正遭到一艘不明飞船的攻击。
Damage report.
损伤报告。
We've sustained heavy damages to the engines.
引擎遭受了严重损坏。
We've lost our warp drive.
我们失去了曲速引擎。
We'll have to attempt to make contact.
我们必须尝试建立联系。
This is Captain Picard of the Starship Enterprise.
我是企业号星舰的皮卡德舰长。
We don't wish to engage.
我们不想交战。
What is the nature of this attack?
这次攻击的性质是什么？
I am Captain Kor of the ship Clothos.
我是克洛索斯号飞船的科尔舰长。
Your ship attacked our search party.
你的飞船攻击了我们的搜索队。
No, you're not doing it right.
不，你演得不对。
Kor doesn't sound like that.
科尔的声音不是那样的。
His voice is deeper.
他的声音更低沉。
I am Captain Kor of the ship Clothos.
我是克洛索斯号飞船的科尔舰长。
Your ship.
你的飞船。
No.
不。
If you can't do an authentic Klingon voice, I'll have to find a more serious Star Trek
如果你不能发出地道的克林贡语声音，我得找一个更认真的《星际迷航》粉丝，一个真正会演戏的，行吗？
fan who can actually act, okay?
一个真正会演戏的，行吗？
But but, I already bought the Klingon suit and the wig.
但是但是，我已经买了克林贡套装和假发。
All right.
好的。
Now it's time for us to take a look at more phrases today in Fluency Builder.
现在是时候在“流利度构建”中看看今天更多的短语了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right.
好的。
So, we've got some phrases here that you can use together with a number of different words,
我们这里有一些短语，你可以和许多不同的词一起使用，对吧？
right?
对。
Absolutely.
当然。
So, the first one, we heard that data said we're under attack.
第一个，我们听到Data说“we're under attack”（我们正遭到攻击）。
We're under attack.
我们正遭到攻击。
Under attack.
遭到攻击。
All right.
好的。
So, if we're under attack, it means that we are being attacked.
如果我们“under attack”，意思是我们正在被攻击。
Someone is shooting guns at you or trying to hurt you or something like that.
有人在向你开枪或试图伤害你之类的。
Okay.
好的。
So, we are under attack.
所以我们正遭到攻击。
Very popular phrase that you would hear in war movies or something.
这是一个在战争电影中很常见的短语。
Definitely.
当然。
Now, you can change this by changing the last word.
现在，你可以通过改变最后一个词来变化这个短语。
We are under fire.
我们正遭到炮火攻击。
Under fire, which basically means the same thing.
遭到炮火攻击，基本上意思相同。
Yeah, except it, when you're under fire, there are guns involved.
是的，除了“under fire”时，涉及枪炮。
Okay.
好的。
So, they're shooting at you.
所以他们在向你射击。
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好的。
We're under attack.
我们正遭到攻击。
We're under fire.
我们正遭到炮火攻击。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
All right.
好的。
Moving on to our second phrase.
继续看第二个短语。
We've sustained heavy damage.
我们遭受了严重损坏。
Sustained heavy damage.
遭受了严重损坏。
So, when you sustain something, you receive it or you undergo this thing.
当你“sustain”（遭受）某物时，你接收或经历了这件事。
So, usually, it's related to injury or to receiving some type of...
所以通常与受伤或接收某种……有关。
Of negative thing.
负面的事情。
Okay.
好的。
So, why don't we listen to some examples of how we could use sustain in context.
我们来听一些例子，看看如何在上下文中使用“sustain”。
Example one.
例子一。
John had a car accident and sustained a fatal injury.
约翰出了车祸，遭受了致命伤。
Example two.
例子二。
The boxer sustained a severe neck injury in the championship fight.
这位拳击手在冠军赛中遭受了严重的颈部损伤。
Example three.
例子三。
Luckily, the warship didn't sustain any serious damage.
幸运的是，这艘战舰没有遭受任何严重损坏。
All right.
好的。
So, you see, we typically sustain something like an injury or damage that is negative.
所以，你看，我们通常用“sustain”来指遭受某种负面的事情，比如受伤或损坏。
Very good.
非常好。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
And our last phrase for today, what is the nature of this attack?
今天我们的最后一个短语是，这次攻击的性质是什么？
What is the nature of?
是什么性质？
Okay.
好的。
So, basically, he's just asking, why are you doing this?
所以，基本上，他只是在问，你为什么这么做？
Right.
对。
Why...
为什么...
What is the reason?
原因是什么？
Yeah.
是的。
What is the purpose?
目的是什么？
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
So, again, we have some more examples of how you could use what is the nature of in different
所以，我们还有一些例子，展示你可以在不同情况下如何使用“是什么性质”
situations.
这个短语。
Example one.
例子一。
What is the nature of your visits to the United States?
你访问美国的性质是什么？
Example two.
例子二。
What is the nature of the threat against our country?
对我们国家的威胁性质是什么？
Example three.
例子三。
The nature of my visit is personal.
我访问的性质是私人的。
Okay.
好的。
So, a great phrase you can use not only when you're talking sci-fi, but in everyday life.
所以，这是一个很棒的短语，不仅可以在谈论科幻时使用，在日常生活中也能用。
Exactly.
没错。
So, why don't we listen now to the dialogue for the last time, and then we'll come back
那么，我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来
and talk a little bit more.
再聊一会儿。
Captain, we are under attack by an unidentified ship.
舰长，我们正遭到一艘不明飞船的攻击。
Damage report.
损伤报告。
We've sustained heavy damages to the engines.
引擎遭受了严重损坏。
We've lost our warp drive.
我们失去了曲速引擎。
We'll have to attempt to make contact.
我们必须尝试建立联系。
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard of the Starship Enterprise.
我是企业号星舰的让-吕克·皮卡德舰长。
We don't wish to engage.
我们不想交战。
What is the nature of this attack?
这次攻击的性质是什么？
I am Captain Kor of the ship Kortos.
我是科托斯号飞船的科尔舰长。
Your ship attacked our search party.
你们的飞船攻击了我们的搜索队。
No, you're not doing it right.
不，你演得不对。
Kor doesn't sound like that.
科尔的声音不是那样的。
His voice is deeper.
他的声音更低沉。
I am Captain Kor of the ship Kortos.
我是科托斯号飞船的科尔舰长。
Your ship...
你们的飞船...
No!
不！
I don't want to do an authentic Klingon voice.
我不想模仿地道的克林贡语声音。
I'll have to find a more serious Star Trek fan who can actually act, okay?
我得找一个更认真的《星际迷航》粉丝，能真正表演的，好吗？
But, but, I already bought the Klingon suit and the wig and...
但是，但是，我已经买了克林贡服装和假发，还有...
Well, Marco, I already admitted that I'm not much of a sci-fi fan, and I don't really know
嗯，马可，我已经承认我不是科幻迷，而且我真的不太了解
anything about Star Trek or Star Wars.
《星际迷航》或《星球大战》的任何东西。
Well, it is a very popular show.
嗯，这是一部非常受欢迎的剧。
I think it started around the 60s or 70s.
我想它大概始于60年代或70年代。
The first version of Star Trek, and well, many, many people follow it now.
《星际迷航》的第一个版本，而且，嗯，现在有很多人追它。
They dress up, they know the secret language that is used on the show, they know the spaceships.
他们打扮成剧中角色，知道剧中使用的秘密语言，了解那些飞船。
It's a big culture.
这是一种庞大的文化。
That's true, and speaking of culture, I think we've got a Star Trek movie coming out pretty
没错，说到文化，我想我们很快会有一部《星际迷航》电影上映，
soon, so some of this language can help you guys understand it a little bit better.
所以这些语言可以帮助你们更好地理解它。
Very good, yeah.
非常好，是的。
So, if you have any other questions or comments related to, not only to science fiction, but
所以，如果你们有任何其他问题或评论，不仅限于科幻，而是
anything in general, please come to the website EnglishPod.com and leave your questions or
任何一般性问题，请访问网站EnglishPod.com，留下你们的问题或
comments.
评论。
Well, thanks for downloading, you guys, and until next time, goodbye!
嗯，感谢下载，各位，下次再见，拜拜！